- 恭喜 - 谢谢
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
莫先生和他朋友将要失业了
Mr Romales and his friends will be out of business.
至少他不会用海洛因口味的香蕉 去支助革命
He won't be using heroin-flavoured bananas to finance revolutions.
不要回酒店 他们会监视你
Don't go back to your hotel, ser. They'll be watching you.
- 一小时后有飞机飞往迈阿密 - 我会上飞机…
- There's a plane to Miami in an hour. - I'll be on it, but.
…但首先我要办点事
first I have some unfinished business to attend to.
对不起
Forgive me.
为什么你总是带着这个东西？
Why do you always wear that thing?
我有轻微的自卑情结
I have a slight inferiority complex.
我刚才在做什么？对了
Where was I?
被电死的
Shocking!
绝对是被电死的
Positively shocking.
《007系列之金手指》
- 感觉如何？- 非常好
- How's this? - It's nice… Very nice.
- 这里？- 再低点 亲爱的
- Just here? - No, a little lower.
我就知道你会被照顾得很好
I thought I'd find you in good hands.
费立斯！你好吗？
Felix! How are you?
- 丁克 来见见费立斯 - 哈罗
- Dink, meet Felix Leiter. - Hello!
- 费立斯 这是丁克 - 嗨 丁克
- Felix, say hello to Dink. - Hi, Dink.
丁克 和费立斯说再见
Dink, say goodbye to Felix.
这是男人之间的事
Man talk.
你精神松懈了 007 让对手如此接近你
You must be slipping, 007, letting the opposition get that close to you.
他们在牙买加更加接近 不是吗？
They got a lot closer to you in Jamaica.
在想什么？我在渡假
What's on your mind? I'm on holiday.
不再是了 伦敦有指示来
Not any more, you're not. Signal from London.
我就知道M让我住最好的旅馆 绝非好意
I knew M wouldn't book me into the best hotel here out of gratitude.
他交待我们替你盯着他
He asked us to keep an eye on him for you.
奥瑞克金手指 听起来像法国指甲油
Auric Goldfinger. Sounds like a French nail varnish!
他是英国人 但口音不像
He's British. But he doesn't sound like it.
大企业家 事业横跨世界 全是合法生意
Big operator, worldwide interests. All seem reputable.
拥有一个全美最好的马场
Owns one of the finest US stud farms.
- 这和华府有什么关联？- 中情局认为他没有问题
- What's the tie-up with Washington? - He's clean.
那里找得到他？
And where do I find him?
那是他的凯子 正在等他
That's his pigeon waiting for him now.
金手指已连赢他一周了
Goldfinger's been taking him to the cleaners every day for a week.
早 西蒙先生 准备开始了吗？
Morning, Mr Simmons! Ready for our little game?
当然准备好了 输了一万元 随时准备好翻本
Sure. When you're ten grand in the hole, you're ready for anything.
- 我能要我的老位子吗？- 你和你的日光浴！
- Could I have my usual seat? - You and your suntan!
金手指是位杰出的玩牌高手
Goldfinger's a fabulous card player.
- 同样赌注？- 加倍
- Same stakes? - Let's double it.
一分5元
Five dollars a point.
- 你说5元吗？- 我总会转运的
- Did you say five? - My luck's gotta change some time.
好的
OK.
我回公司发电报给M 说你已在办案了
I'll get back and cable M you're on the job.
- 其他的资料在晚饭时再告诉我 - 等一会打给你
- Fill me in on the rest at dinner. - Fine. I'll call you later.
- 四 - 这么快？
- Four. - So soon?
几分？
How many?
7 12 18 32…
7, 12, 18, 32…
44.
小姐？
Miss?
你在…
Hey, what are you…
这是金手指先生的套房！
That's Mr Goldfinger's suite!
我知道
Yes, I know.
你很甜
You're very sweet.
他刚拿一张梅花老K 让他有59分
He just drew the king of clubs. That makes his count 59.
他有红心同花顺 8 9 10
He's got a diamond run: Eight, nine, ten.
他手上留着黑桃6 我想他认为你会要
He's holding on to the six of spades, so I guess he thinks you want it.
上一张牌是红心8
That last draw was the eight of hearts.
他需要老K和皇后
He needs kings and queens.
- 你是谁？- 邦德 詹姆斯邦德
- Who are you? - Bond. James Bond.
快些
Come on, come on!
这才像话！
That's more like it!
- 你叫什么名字？- 吉儿
- What's your name? - Jill.
- 哪位吉儿？- 吉儿马特生
- Jill who? - Jill Masterson.
- 告诉我 吉儿 他为何这么做？- 他喜欢赢
- Tell me, Jill. Why does he do it? - He likes to win.
- 你为何这么做？- 他请我的
- Why do you do it? - He pays me.
- 他只请你做这个？- 还有和他一起露面
- Is that all he pays you for? - And for being seen with him.
只是露面？
Just seen?
是的
Just seen.
我放心了
I'm so glad.
你人太好 不该卷入这种件事
You're much too nice to be mixed up in anything like this, you know.
听着 金手指 你的运气变了
Now hear this, Goldfinger. Your luck has just changed.
我怀疑迈阿密警方不会纵容…你这种行为的
I doubt if the Miami Beach police would take kindly to what you're doing.
同意就点头
Nod your head if you agree.
点头
Nod.
很好 现在起开始输 金手指
Good! Now start losing, Goldfinger.
一万元如何？
Shall we say $10, 000?
大方些
No, let's be generous.
算一万五好了
Let's make it $15, 000.
我能看吗？
May I see?
今天我很顺手！
Hell, I can see this is really my day!
赢了！
Gin!
通话完毕
Over and out.
这够他忙上一阵
That should keep him occupied for quite some time.
邦德先生 我开始喜欢你了
I'm beginning to like you, Mr Bond.
叫我詹姆斯
Call me James.
我好久没有遇上你这种人了 詹姆斯
More than anyone I've met in a long time… James.
关于这点 我们打算怎么办？
What on earth are we going to do about it?
- 是啊 怎么办呢？- 晚饭时再告诉你
- Yes. What? - I'll tell you at dinner.
去哪里？
Where?
城里最好的地方
Well, I know the best place in town.
WEBS电台新闻报导
Station WEDS brings you the latest in world news.
华府消息 总统今天下午…
Washington. At the White House today,
…在白宫说很满意
the President said he was entirely satisfied…
这下有两人很满意
That makes two of us.
- 喂 - 我是莱特
- Hello. - Leiter here.
费立斯
Felix! Well, now?
什么？吃晚饭？
What's that? Dinner?
对不起
No, look, I'm sorry.
我没空 有重要事情
I can't. Something big's come up.
早餐如何
How about breakfast?
不要太早
OK Not too early.
- 9点打给你 - 好 9点好
- I'll call you around nine. - Yes, nine o'clock will be fine.
- 再见 - 晚安
- So long, James. - Good night, Felix.
放太久就不冰了
It's lost its chill!
- 噢 怎么 你！- 冰箱里面还有一瓶
- Why, you! - There's another in the fridge.
- 谁需要啊？- 亲爱的女孩 有些事 还没到时间就不能做
- Who needs it? - My dear, some things just aren't done.
比如喝唐派里昂53年的香槟…
Such as drinking Dom Pignon '53…
…温度却超过38度
above a temperature of 38?Fahrenheit.
就像不戴耳机 听披头四的歌
That's as bad as listening to the Beatles without earmuffs.
“热情之液”在哪？
Now… where is this passion juice?
吉儿
Jill?
什么事 邦德先生
Yes, Mr Bond?
请接海滩79432 119号房
Beach 79432. Room 119.
- 喂？- 费立斯？
- Hello? - Hello, Felix.
马上过来
Get over here right away.
- 怎么了？- 那女孩死了
- What's happened? - The girl's dead.
- 丁克？- 不 吉儿马特生
- Dink? - No, Masterson. Jill Masterson.
全身被涂漆 金漆
And she's covered in paint. Gold paint.
金的？
Gold?
全身？
All over?
她是因为皮肤窒息而死 曾发生在歌舞女郎身上
She died of skin suffocation. It can happen to cabaret dancers.
只要在背脊上留个面积 让皮肤能够呼吸…
You should leave a small bare patch at the base of the spine.
…就会没事
to allow the skin to breathe.
- 很明显的 有人没有留面积 - 我知道是谁
- Someone obviously didn't. - And I know who.
这不是私人恩怨 007 这是任务
This isn't a personal vendetta, 007.
跟别的任务一样
It's an assignment like any other.
如果你不能冷静客观处理…
And if you can't treat it as such, coldly and objectively,
…008可以接替
008 can replace you.
你就是认不清楚自己
You've hardly distinguished yourself.
你应该监视金手指先生 不是去借用他女友
You were to observe Mr Goldfinger. Not borrow his girlfriend.
就因如此 金手指去了欧洲 因为主的恩赐…
Instead, Goldfinger goes to Europe and it's only thanks to Leiter.
…莱特和我对 华府的英国大使馆施压力…
and my diplomatic intervention.
你才没有被迈阿密警方扣留
that you're not being held by the Miami Beach police!
我知道我自己的缺点
Sir, I am aware of my shortcomings.
我准备依你的建议…继续此项任务…
But I'm prepared to continue this assignment in the spirit you suggest.
…如果我知道是 怎么回事的话…
if I knew what it was about,
…长官
sir.
你对黄金了解多少？不是金漆 是金砖
What do you know about gold? Not paint, bullion.
见到时我会知道
I know it when I see it.
7点这里见
Meet me here at seven.
穿礼服
Black tie.
钱班霓 你对黄金了解多少？
What do you know about gold, Moneypenny?
我只知道你戴的那种
The only gold I know about is the kind you wear.
戴在左手无名指那种
You know, on the third finger of your left hand.
总有一天 要好好查查
One of these days we really must look into that.
今晚如何？过来吃晚饭
What about tonight? Come round for dinner.
我烤蛋糕给你吃
and I'll cook you a beautiful angel cake.
没什么事让我更高兴了
Nothing would give me greater pleasure.
但我生意上有约会
but unfortunately I do have a… business appointment.
这是我听过最差的藉口
That's the flimsiest excuse you've ever given me!
有的女孩就有那种运气
Some girls have all the luck!
- 她是谁？詹姆斯 - “她”是我 钱班霓小姐
- Who is she, James? - She is me, Miss Moneypenny,
请你别和007胡闹了 他跟我一起吃晚饭
and kindly omit the customary by-play with 007. He's dining with me.
我不希望他迟到
and I don't want him to be late.
那我还有希望了
So there's hope for me yet?
钱班霓
Moneypenny…
你什么时候会开始相信我？
Won't you ever believe me?
英伦银行是官方存放
We here at the Bank of England.
金块之地…
are the official depository for gold bullion.
…如美国肯塔基州的 诺克堡一样
Just as Fort Knox, Kentucky, is for the United States.
我们知道彼此有多少金块 在手上 有多少存放在别的银行
We know the amounts we each hold and the amounts deposited in other banks.
也能估计工业界持有多少
We can estimate what is being held for industrial purposes.
能让两国政府建立…
Thus, both governments can establish.
…美元和英镑的真正价值
the true value of the dollar and the pound.
近来 我们相当关切 非法交易
Consequently, we are concerned with unauthorised leakages.
你是指走私
I take it you mean smuggling.
是的
Yes.
黄金能被溶化后再还原 而且不会留下痕迹…
Gold, gentlemen, which can be melted down and recast, is all but untraceable,
…让黄金 不像是钻石 成为走私最理想…
which makes it, unlike diamonds, ideal for smuggling,
…吸引到最大和最聪明的罪犯
attracting the biggest and most ingenious criminals.
- 谢谢 就这样 - 谢谢
- Thank you, Brunskill. That'll be all. - Thank you, sir.
再来一些令人失望的白兰地
Have a little more of this… rather disappointing brandy.
- 怎么了？- 这是30年老而且
- What's the matter with it? - I'd say it was a 30-year-old Fine,
搅拌不完全…
indifferently blended, sir.
…加了太多香料的酒
With an overdose of Bons Bois.
史上校正在演讲 007
Colonel Smithers is giving the lecture, 007.
金手指在苏黎世 和阿姆斯特丹…
Gentlemen, Mr Goldfinger has gold bullion on deposit.
…克拉兹 香港都存有 价值二千万英镑金块
in Zurich, Amsterdam, Caracas and Hong Kong, worth 20 million.
- 大多数来自本国 - 为什么要提走？
- Most of it came from this country. - Why move it?
因为各国的价格不同
The price of gold varies from country to country.
这里买一盎斯30元 巴基斯坦可卖到110元…
If you buy it here at $30 an ounce, you can sell it in, say, Pakistan at $110…
…价钱变3倍
and triple your money.
- 如果他有设备溶化它的话 - 他有吗？
- If you have facilities for melting it down. - And has he?
身为正当的金块交易者 金手指他…
Apart from being a legitimate bullion dealer, Mr Goldfinger poses…
不 这不公平
No, that's not quite fair.
在他众多生意中 他是一名正当的国际珠宝商
Is, among his many other interests, a legitimate international jeweller.
他能合法的适度的操作冶金设备
He's legally entitled to operate modest metallurgical installations.
他英国的工厂就在肯特
His British one is down in Kent.
目前为止仍查不出
We've failed to discover how he transfers his gold overseas.
他如何把金子转到海外
And Lord knows we've tried.
如果你的部门 能查出他在违法…
If your department can establish that it is done illegally,
…那银行就能扣查他的黄金
the bank can take action to recover most of his holdings.
该是我和金手指见面的时候了
I think it's time Mr Goldfinger and I met.
当然
Socially, of course.
我正等着你这么说
I was hoping you'd say that.
也许会牵扯到金手指先生 蛮专业的生意上的话题
It might lead to a business talk… Mr Goldfinger's kind of business.
- 我需要诱饵 - 我同意
- I'll need some sort of bait. - I quite agree.
掳获纳粹藏在脱兹湖时 留下的唯一一块
This is the only one we have from the Nazi hoard in Lake Toplitz.
当然还有其他的
But there are undoubtedly others.
邦德先生可以任意使用…
Mr Bond can make whatever use of it he thinks fit.
…不过 当然要归还
Providing he returns it, of course.
价值五千英镑
It's worth 5, 000.
你明早向Q拿黄金 还有其他装备
You'll draw it from Q branch with your equipment in the morning.
当然
Of course, sir.
- 早 Q - 早 007
- Morning, Q. - Morning, 007.
这边请
This way, please.
今早大伙儿都很忙啊
My, we are busy this morning!
还不够完美
It's not perfected yet.
- 我的班特利车呢？- 恐怕已经过时
- Where's my Bentley? - It's had its day, I'm afraid.
- 它从未令我失望过 - M的命令
- But it's never let me down. - M's orders, 007.
你将用改装过的 奥斯丁克马田DB5
You'll be using this Aston Martin DB5 with modifications.
请注意
Now, pay attention, please.
防弹玻璃…两侧和后窗都是
Windscreen-bulletproof. As are the side and the rear windows.
各种车牌
Revolving number plates, naturally.
各国都适用
Valid all countries.
这是小发报器 叫做“归者”
Here's a nice little transmitting device, called a homer.
压住后面拉开就行了 知道吗？
You prime it by pressing that back like this. You see?
更小的模式 现在已经是标准配备…
The smaller model is now standard field issue,
…可以放在鞋后跟
to be fitted into the heel of your shoe.
大型的具有磁性
Its larger brother is magnetic.
可以利用车内追踪荧幕…而不被发现
Right. It'll be concealed in the car you're trailing while you keep out of sight.
接受器
Reception.
在表板上
on the dashboard here.
荧幕装置 有效距离150英里
Audiovisual, range 150 miles.
聪明而有效
Ingenious, and useful too.
能让男人偷闲一下
Allow a man to stop off for a quick one en route.
我们多年来追求完美和 耐心的研究…
It has not been perfected out of years of patient research.
…不是为了这个目的
entirely for that purpose, 007.
顺便提一下 我很感激你…把它还有 别的装备一起归还
And incidentally we'd appreciate its return, along with your other equipment.
至少要有一次 在你出完任务后 能完整的送回来
Intact, for once, when you return from the field.
你不知道在外工作的辛苦血泪！
You'd be surprised at the wear and tear that goes on out there in the field.
- 还有其他的吗？- 如果你专心的话
- Anything else? - I won't keep you for more than an hour.
应该不会超过一小时
if you give me your undivided attention.
我们做了有趣的改装
We've installed some interesting modifications.
看到这扶手了吗？
You see this arm here?
打开顶盖 里面是防卫性控制器
Now, open the top and inside are your defence mechanism controls.
烟幕 滑油
Smoke screen. Oil slick.
后窗防弹幕…
Rear bulletproof screen.
…左、右前置机枪
And left and right front-wing machine guns.
这个我要特别介绍 看见这排挡杆吗？
Now, this one I'm particularly keen about. You see the gear lever here?
如果把顶盖拿掉
Now, if you take the top off,
有个红色小按钮
you'll find a little red button.
- 不论你做什么 不要碰它 - 为什么？
- Whatever you do, don't touch it. - And why not?
会把车顶掀掉…
Because you'll release this section of the roof.
…并把客座椅弹射出来
and engage and fire the passenger ejector seat.
弹射座位？你在开玩笑
Ejector seat? You're joking!
我从不对我的工作开玩笑
I never joke about my work, 007.
- 准备好了吗？- 好了
- Ready, Blacking? - Yes, sir.
有位老会员也来 也是个高手
An old member has dropped by, sir. Same handicap as yours.
- 你想和他较量吗？- 他在哪里？
- I wondered if you'd rather play with him. - Where is he?
- 邦德先生 - 是的？
- Mr Bond. - Yes?
这是金手指先生
This is Mr Goldfinger.
- 幸会 - 幸会
- How do you do? - How do you do?
- 可以开始了 第一洞有空了 - 很好
- You can leave now. The first tee is clear. - Fine.
- 我会找位球童帮你拿球袋 - 太好了
- Hawker will caddy for you, Mr Bond. - That'll be splendid.
一球一先令好吗？
Shall we make it a shilling a hole?
- 我带了一些装备 - 嗯 可以
- I'll take some tees. - Yes, of course.
你要原谅这位“怪侠”
You must excuse "Oddjob", Mr Bond.
他是个好仆人
He's an admirable manservant.
而且是个哑巴 但不是个好球童
but mute. He's not a very good caddy.
高尔夫球在韩国 还不是全国运动
Golf is not yet the national game of Korea.
这次碰面不是巧合吧？
This meeting is not a coincidence.
你玩什么把戏？
What's your game, Mr Bond?
- 我的把戏？- 你不是来打高尔夫球的
- My game? - You didn't come here to play golf.
1940年在艾森塑造成的
A 1940 smelt from the Weigenhaler foundry at Essen.
- 总数约600 - 1944年失踪
- Part of a smelt of 600. - They vanished in 1944.
当纳粹战败时
When the Nazis were on the run.
- 你还有吗？- 有 同样一个来源
- Do you have access to more? - Yes, from the same source.
有趣
Interesting.
- 还剩两个洞 - 对 不分胜负
- Two holes to go. - Yes, and all square.
不反对提高赌注？
Then you have no objection to increasing the stakes?
- 你想如何赌？- 当然是你那块金块
- No. What do you have in mind? - The bar of gold you have, naturally.
- 值五千英镑 - 我用同值现金
- It's worth 5, 000. - Oh, I'll stake the cash equivalent!
当然
Naturally.
完全遵照高尔夫球规定？
Strict rules of golf?
当然
But of course.
运气不好 球落在乱草中
Bad luck, you're in the rough.
真可惜 在这里
What a pity. Here it is.
那个不是 他是一号球
No, it's not. He plays a Slazenger 1.
完全遵照高尔夫球规定 5分钟快到了
Strict rules of golf, Goldfinger. Five minutes are almost up.
找不到球罚一棍
A lost ball will cost you stroke and distance.
我仍在训练他当球童
I'm still training him as a caddy.
也蛮成功的
Successfully, too.
1号球？
Slazenger No. 1.
好
Good.
如果那是他原先的球 我就是球王了
If that's his original ball, I'm Arnold Palmer.
那不是
It isn't.
- 你怎么知道？- 我正站在它上面
- How do you know? - I'm standing on it.
你这老狐…
Why, you crafty old…
不要碰它
Leave it.
- 用你找到的球？- 对 7号球
- The ball you found, sir? - Yes, Slazenger 7.
我们和金手指先生开个玩笑
Let's have a little fun with Mr Goldfinger.
要我标示还是先打？
Like me to mark it or knock it in?
打吧
Play it.
- 此击一决胜负？- 对
- This for a half. - That's right.
还有一洞 关键性的一洞
One to go, that will be the clincher.
好
Fine.
你把球换过了吗？
Did you switch 'em, sir?
- 那骗到他了 - 如果他没注意到换球的话.
- Then we've got him. - If he doesn't notice the switch.
- 应该你先发球 - 没有关系
- It's your honour, sir. - It's all right.
低于5棍
Down in five.
我必须打进才赢 对吗？
I have to sink this to halve the game, right?
- 你赢了 - 似乎我比你打得好
- You win, Goldfinger. - It seems I'm too good for you!
你打的是1号球吧？
You play a Slazenger 1, don't you?
- 是 为什么？- 这是7号球
- Yes, why? - This is a Slazenger 7.
这是我的球
Here's my Penfold Hearts.
你一定在18洞时打错球
You must have played the wrong ball on the 18th fairway.
我们是完全照规定打球
We are playing strict rules, so.
恐怕你这个洞和整个比赛都输了
I'm afraid you lose the hole and the match.
她真美 她是凡顿3型 37年的车 不是吗？
She's a beauty. Phantom III, '37, isn't she?
- 你很聪明而且阅历丰富 - 谢谢
- You are clever and resourceful, Mr Bond. - Thank you.
也许太聪明了 我们曾交过两次手 就让它这样吧
Perhaps too clever. Twice our paths have crossed. Let's leave it at that.
第一次交手时就应该说服了你
Didn't our first meeting convince you?
我知道了 你担心我不跟你再打一场
I see. You're worried about me not giving you a return game.
我们彼此心知肚明
Both of us know perfectly well what we're talking about, Mr Bond.
但我认为有必要再提醒你
But I see that it is necessary to remind you.
“怪侠”！
"Oddjob"!
很多人想干涉我的事…
Many people have tried to involve themselves in my affairs.
…却都失败
Unsuccessfully.
了不起！但不知 俱乐部的秘书会怎么说？
Remarkable. But what does the club secretary have to say?
没有什么 邦德先生
Nothing, Mr Bond.
俱乐部是我的
I own the club.
你大概要现金支票
I assume you want the cheque made out to cash.
这样会令人满意
That would be perfectly satisfactory.
再会 邦德先生
Goodbye, Mr Bond.
我相信这是你的
I believe this is yours.
请各位注意
Can I have your attention, please?
英航最后声明…
British United Air Ferries announce the final call.
…前往日内瓦的VF四百班机
for the departure of their VF400 flight to Geneva.
…即将起飞…
British United Air Ferries announce the departure of their VF400 flight to Geneva.
邦德先生
Mr Bond!
我帮你安排了半小时后 搭下班飞机飞往日内瓦
I've got you booked on the next flight to Geneva, leaving in half an hour.
- 谢谢你 - 好
- Thank you very much. - Right, sir.
007 守纪律
Discipline, 007.
守纪律
Discipline.
你不要紧吧？让我帮你
Are you all right? Here, let me help you.
- 你能活着真幸运 - 别指望我会感激你
- You know, you're lucky to be alive. - No thanks to you.
你该再靠边点
You should've pulled over further.
你看看
Look at them!
两轮一起爆 我从没见过
A double blowout. I've never seen one of these before.
- 新的车胎怎么会… - 也许是次货
- How could new tyres… - A defect of some kind, most likely.
很高兴只是车毁而已
I'm so glad it's the car and not you.
你不像短命的女孩
You don't look like a girl who should be ditched.
别说了 请带我到最近的修车厂
Never mind that. Please take me to a garage.
当然
Certainly.
我叫邦德
By the way, my name is Bond, Ja…
请尽快
As quickly as possible.
- 我来拿 - 当然
- I'll take that. - Yes, of course.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name, by the way?
桑姆 提莉桑姆
Soames. Tilly Soames.
来打猎的吗？
Here for the hunting season?
我也有一个这种箱子
I had a case just like that one.
是我的冰刀
It's for my ice skates.
不错的运动
Lovely sport.
- 你在哪里溜冰？- 圣莫瑞兹
- Where do you skate? - St Moritz.
我没有听过这时候那里会结冰
I didn't know there was ice there this time of the year.
那里有修车厂
There's a garage.
换新车胎需要24小时 附近有间酒店
They say it'll take 24 hours to get new tyres. There's a hotel nearby.
- 我送你去 - 不用了
- Jump in. I'll run you down. - That won't be necessary.
我不愿单独留下你
I hate to leave you here alone.
我能照顾自己
I can take care of myself.
我相信你能
Yes, I'm sure you can.
不要忘记写信
Well… don't forget to write.
走私是种艺术
Smuggling is an art, Mr Ling.
艺术的标准是
And art requires…
我18K金的手工打造的 劳斯莱斯车身
In this case, the bodywork of my Rolls Royce is 18-carat gold.
我们在这里分解它
We dismantle it here.
我们用这特制的炉炼出…
Reduce the gold in this special furnace, which in turn…
重量约有两吨的金砖
…weighing approximately two tons.
我平均一年六次 坐这车到大陆
I make six trips a year to Europe in the Rolls Royce, Mr Ling.
暂缓你其他的活动 是明智的
It would be wiser to suspend your other activities.
全心执行满贯计划…
Mr Ling, please assure your principals.
…是我第一要务
Operation Grand Slam will have my undivided attention…
放开我 你快弄断我的背了
Let me go! You're breaking my back!
- 你在这里做什么？- 我要杀了他
- What the hell are you doing here? - I want to kill him!
- 杀谁？- 金手指
- Kill who? - Goldfinger.
- 我要他活着 - 我要他死 他杀了我姐姐
- Well, I want him alive. - I want him dead! He killed my sister!
T.M.泰莉麦特生
TM. Tilly Masterson.
我记得你姐姐吉儿 和他在迈阿密对她做的事
I knew your sister Jill. I know what he did to her.
你不了解！放开我！
No, you don't! Let me go!
- 如果你要杀他 为何对我开枪？- 我不是 我是对他开枪
- So why did you shoot at me? - I didn't. I was shooting at him!
枪法太差劲了
Well, you're a lousy shot.
这里有人枪法很好
But somebody else around here isn't.
走
Come on.
快上车 我应付他
Get in the car. I'll take care of him.
我告诉你时 你跑向那树丛
Run for that bracken when I tell you.
快跑！
Now!
007 晚安
Good evening, 007.
我叫詹姆斯邦德
My name is James Bond.
这种特殊行业的佼佼者
And members of your curious profession are few in number.
你被一位和你一样有…
You have been recognised.
…杀人执照的对手 认出来了
Let's say by one of your opposite numbers, who is also licensed to kill.
你的车很有趣！
That interesting car of yours!
我也有新玩具
I, too, have a new toy, but.
但更实用
considerably more practical.
你看到的工业用雷射…
You are looking at an industrial laser,
…能产生非比寻常的光
which emits an extraordinary light, unknown in nature.
能发射到月球
It can project a spot on the moon.
或近距离内切割金属 让你见识一下
Or at closer range, cut through solid metal. I will show you.
这是黄金
This is gold, Mr Bond.
我这生中最喜欢的颜色…
All my life, I've been in love with its colour,
…光泽和无可比拟的特性
its brilliance, its divine heaviness.
欢迎任何增加 我存量的企业…
I welcome any enterprise that will increase my stock,
…都列入考量
which is considerable.
你表达了你的意见 谢谢你的示范
I think you've made your point. Thank you for the demonstration.
小心选择你的妙语 那可能是你最后一次了
Choose your next witticism carefully, Mr Bond. It may be your last.
前两次交手的目的 我已很清楚
The purpose of our two encounters is now very clear to me.
我不想被分散注意力 晚安 邦德先生
I do not intend to be distracted by another. Good night, Mr Bond.
你希望我招供？
Do you expect me to talk?
不 我要你死
No, Mr Bond! I expect you to die!
你没有事可以告诉我的 我全都知道了
There is nothing you can talk to me about that I don't already know.
你忘了一件事
You're forgetting one thing.
如果我不报到 008就会接替我
If I fail to report, 008 replaces me.
我相信他会更成功
I trust he will be more successful.
他知道我所知的
He knows what I know.
邦德先生 你什么都不知道
You know nothing, Mr Bond.
比如说满贯计划
Operation Grand Slam, for instance.
你无意中听到这几个字…
Two words you may have overheard.
…你和组织中的任何人 不可能明白其中含意
which cannot have any significance to you or anyone in your organisation.
你能冒这个险吗？
Can you afford to take that chance?
你说得对
You are quite right, Mr Bond.
你活着对我较有价值
You are worth more to me alive.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我叫普西葛罗尔
My name is Pussy Galore.
我一定在做梦
I must be dreaming.
我以为我死了
I thought I'd wake up dead.
麻醉枪 令你不省人事
Tranquilliser gun. Knockout shot.
原来如此
I see.
很高兴来此
I'm delighted to be here.
不过 这是哪里？
And, by the way, where is here?
3万5千英尺高空 往西南方 正飞过纽芬兰
35, 000 feet flying southwest over Newfoundland.
难怪耳鸣
That explains the humming.
你在金手指私人飞机上 正飞往巴尔的摩
That means you're in Mr Goldfinger's Lockheed JetStar, heading for Baltimore.
- 你是他的客人 - 很荣幸
- And you're his guest. - I'm honoured.
我不知道他这么喜欢我陪他
I never realised he enjoyed my company that much.
不会一路都那么好玩的
I don't suppose it'll be all fun and games.
美丽
Mei-Lei.
需要什么吗？邦德先生？
Can I do something for you, Mr Bond?
只要来杯酒 马丁尼 要摇动的…不要搅拌的
Just a drink. A martini, shaken not stirred.
- 你也来一杯吗？- 当值时不喝
- Won't you join me? - Not on duty.
我是金手指先生的私人机师
I'm Mr Goldfinger's personal pilot.
是吗？
You are?
多私人？
And just how personal is that?
我是个好飞行员
I'm a damn good pilot.
如此而已
Period!
这是个好消息
Well, that's good news. By the way,
- 主人呢？- 他先去了
- where is our host? - He flew on ahead.
谢谢
Thank you.
敬满贯计划！
Here's to Operation Grand Slam.
这次将是值得纪念的飞行
This should be a memorable flight.
你不必表现魅力了 我免疫的
You can turn off the charm. I'm immune.
55分钟后 我们会在…
We'll be landing in Baltimore,
…巴尔的摩的机场降落 进入美国领土
our port of entry into the United States, in 55 minutes.
美丽…
Mei-Lei.
…到达时我想穿正式点
I would like to arrive more appropriately dressed.
我的行李跟我一样 存活下来了吗？
Did any of my luggage survive with me?
随身手提箱？
And my attach?case?
对不起 黑色手提箱 检查时已经损坏
Black attach?case damaged when examined. So sorry.
不需要道歉
Apologies quite unnecessary.
辛尼 叫美丽注意他
Sydney, tell Mei-Lei to keep an eye on him.
20分钟后降落
We'll be landing in 20 minutes.
你要乖点还是玩狠的？
Do you want to play it easy… or the hard way?
这不是麻醉枪
And this isn't a tranquilliser.
你对飞机比枪了解得多
Pussy, you know a lot more about planes than guns.
这是史密斯威森45手枪
That's a Smith & Wesson. 45.
如果你近距离开枪 子弹会穿过我和机身…
If you fire this close, the bullet will pass through me and the fuselage.
…像火焰枪穿过奶油一样
like a blowtorch through butter.
机身内压力减低 我们全会被吸出机外
The cabin will depressurise and we'll be sucked into outer space together.
如果你想这样去美国
If that's how you want to arrive, you're welcome.
请便 我喜欢比较容易的方式
As for me, I prefer the easier way.
合情合理
That's very sensible.
何况呆在金手指四周的 节目很精彩
And there's so much going on around Mr Goldfinger,
我不会不接受他热情款待
I wouldn't dream of not accepting his… hospitality.
他也会很高兴见到你
He'll be very glad to see you, too.
你喜欢以身试险 不是吗？
You like close shaves, don't you?
华盛顿电话 绿色电话
Washington, sir. On the green scrambler.
- 我是M - 是莱特 长官
- M here. - Leiter, sir.
是关于007 我们收到他的讯号
It's about 007, sir. We picked up his homer signal.
他刚降落在巴尔的摩
from Friendship Airport, Baltimore, where he's just landed.
巴尔的摩？真高兴他通知我们
Baltimore? Nice of him to let us know.
我们听说他最后在瑞士
Last we heard, he was in Switzerland.
他坐私人喷射机进入的
He came in on a private jet, ex Geneva.
机主是老朋友 金手指
Registered to our old friend Auric Goldfinger.
很高兴他有进展 留意他
I'm glad he's making progress. Keep an eye on him for us.
飞行目的地是肯德基 蓝草机场
Bluegrass Field, Kentucky, is their final destination.
别打草惊蛇
Don't charge in on him and spoil anything, will you?
此刻他一定掌握全局了
He's evidently well on top at the moment.
- 邦德先生 请 - 当然
- Mr Bond. - Of course.
随时候教
Any time.
谢谢
Thank you.
小心步阶 机长
Do mind your step, Captain.
乖点
Just keep playing it easy.
看一切是否安排好？
Mei-Lei, will you see everything's all right with Mr Goldfinger?
当然
And I'll see you surprisingly soon.
- 这团体很专业 - 应该的 是我训练
- Talented chaps. - They should be. I trained them.
走
Come on.
普西 你是个多才多艺的女人
You're a woman of many parts, Pussy.
我相信肯德基的酒 和泉水一定极佳
I believe the bourbon and branch water is rather splendid here in Kentucky.
现在我们不用当值了 也许
Well, now that we're both off duty, perhaps…
礼貌 “怪侠”
Manners, "Oddjob".
我以为你见到女子都会脱帽
I thought you always took your hat off to a lady.
- 他杀害像你这种小女孩 - 还有小男孩
- You know, he kills little girls like you. - Little boys, too.
- 预演得很顺利 - 很好！
- Dress rehearsal went like a dream. - Good.
今晚宣布最后简报 现在解散
Your final briefing is tonight. That'll be all for now.
欢迎来到奥瑞克养马场
Welcome to Auric Stud, Mr Bond.
很美的动物 不是吗？
Lovely animal, isn't she?
比马主人还美得多了
Certainly better bred than the owner.
带邦德先生去他的睡房
Show Mr Bond to his quarters, please.
费立斯
Felix!
- 也许该直接闯进去 - 如果需要我们他会大叫
- Maybe we should just drop in on him. - He'll shout if he needs us.
金手指先生 他们都到了
They're all here, Mr Goldfinger.
噢 对 谢谢 基区
Oh, yes! Thank you, Kisch.
索罗那小子 会把鞋磨个洞
That guy Solo's gonna wear a hole in his shoes.
嗯 我喜欢
Yeah, I like this!
各位
Gentlemen!
为何我们没被告知纽约和 西海岸也有份？
Goldfinger, why weren't we told New York and the West Coast were in on this?
看谁在说话
Look who's talking!
我不和芝加哥做生意
I do not do business with Chicago.
我以为我们有个 秘密的生意要处理
I thought we had a private business deal to settle.
现在却发现参加了大团聚
Now I find I'm attending a hoods' convention.
我已交货了 钱呢？
Goldfinger, I made a delivery. Where is my money?
- 我也交货了 - 你们全交货了
- I made a delivery, too. - You all made the deliveries we agreed.
你欠我一百万元
And you owe me one million bucks.
我欠你们每人
I owe each of you a million.
一百万金块
in gold bullion.
那就付钱！
So, pay!
各位 你们今天可以 拿到一百万…
Gentlemen, you can have the million today.
…或是明天拿到一千万！
Or ten millions tomorrow.
一千万？
Did you say ten million?
只等明天银行早上开门
As soon as my bank opens in the morning.
银行周日不营业
Banks don't open on Sunday.
我的银行会营业
My bank will.
这撞球台玩什么花样？
What's with that trick pool table?
- 掩护！- 守住大门
- Cover him! - Hey, cover those doors.
开灯！
Turn those lights back on!
你玩什么把戏？金手指
What are you trying to pull, Goldfinger?
各位 不必紧张
There is no cause for alarm, gentlemen.
我不喜欢被困着 地图有何作用？
I don't like being cooped up like this. What's that map doing there?
这是我的银行
This is my bank.
存放在诺克斯堡的黄金
The gold depository at Fort Knox, gentlemen.
里面有150亿元…
In its vaults are $15 billion.
…供应全美国的
The entire gold supply.
黄金存货
of the United States.
抢劫诺克斯堡？
Knock off Fort Knox!
- 有钥匙吗？- 差不多
- Got a key or somethin'? - Of a kind.
那里有3万5千名军队
There are 35, 000 troops stationed around there!
4万1千名
41, 000.
谁来制服他们？
And who's gonna say boo to them, Goldfinger?
- 怎么回事？- 这是什么？
- What's going on here? - What is this?
- 地板 - 这是什么？
- The floor! - What is this? A merry-go-round?
人类已登上额菲尔士峰…
Man has climbed Mount Everest,
…深入海底
gone to the bottom of the ocean.
发射火箭到月球
He has fired rockets to the moon.
分裂原子
Split the atom.
创造了…
Achieved miracles.
…人类极限能力下的奇迹 除了犯罪以外！
in every field of human endeavour… except crime!
黑道人物将会震惊世界
The underworld will applaud for centuries!
- 废话少说 - 说重点
- Cut the commercial! - Get to the point!
你在浪费我的时间 金库是攻不破的
It's pointless. The depository's impregnable.
- 金库防爆 电网 - 请耐心点！
- The joint is bombproof, electrified… - Bear with me, please!
诺克斯堡也是个银行
Fort Knox is a bank. Like any other.
也许更大受更多保护 但还是间银行
Larger, better protected perhaps, but nonetheless a bank!
它可以 我想该说…
It can be… I think the expression is.
…爆破！
blown.
我的计划傻瓜也能办到
My plan is foolproof, gentlemen!
叫做…满贯计划
I call it Operation Grand Slam.
我投注15年的心血
I have devoted 15 years of my life to it.
每个细节都仔细核对 准备妥当
Every detail has been scrupulously prepared.
每件事都考虑过
Every eventuality has been considered.
这个计划会分秒不差进行
We'll operate on a split-second schedule.
你的组织 夜先生
Your organisation, Mr Midnight,
负责运送金属罐…通过加拿大边界
brought a batch of these canisters across the Canadian border.
内装着雕尔塔9号
They contain Delta 9.
- 是什么？- 无色无味的神经毒气
- Delta 9? What's that? - An invisible nerve gas.
发射后15分钟扩散…
which disperses 15 minutes after inducing complete… unconsciousness.
…能让人昏迷24小时
for 24 hours.
明天凌晨…
Tomorrow at dawn,
…我飞行马戏团的飞机师 普西小姐
the flying circus of my personal pilot, Miss Pussy Galore,
会把它撒在大气层
will spray it into the atmosphere.
一旦扩散 整个军队所有人全昏迷…
Once the population, including the military, has been immobilised.
…我的攻击部队 由史先生
my task force, which Mr Strap and his people.
将他们从墨西哥偷渡来此…
smuggled across the Rio Grande from Mexico,
…会乘坐机动车辆经过 通到金库前…
will approach Fort Knox in motorised equipment.
…和格瓦道交接的…布李街…
along Bullion Boulevard, which runs past the depository here.
…到达诺克斯堡
and intersects with Gold Vault Road.
这道金库周围的围墙…
This fence surrounding the depository,
…正如史先生提醒 有电流
as Mr Strap reminded us, is electrified.
将被炸毁
It will be dynamited!
我的部队将由 主要通道摧毁一切
My task force will then move to the main entrance and demolish it.
怎么摧毁 请问？
How, may I ask?
索罗先生 靠你了 经由你在运输界的影响力
You made that possible, Mr Solo. By using your influence in shipping circles.
不用通过海关的检查…
to bring through customs uninspected.
…箱外打上“机械零件”
a consignment labelled machine parts.
剩下的只是要进入这个…存放金块的金库
All that will then remain is to descend to the vaults where the bullion is stored.
- 我听够了 - 让他去完成
- I've heard enough. - Let him finish.
你不反对的话 我现在拿我的钱
If you have no objection… I'll take my money now.
索罗 怎么了？大到你无法应付？
What's the matter, Solo? Too big for you to handle?
我们该尊重索罗先生的决定
We must respect Mr Solo's decision.
请恕我失陪 我先招呼他
Excuse me for a moment while I take care of him. Make yourselves comfortable.
普西！
Pussy!
谁教你柔道？
Who taught you judo?
你拿走的枪
The gun you took.
枪
The gun.
枪 当然啦！
The gun, of course.
改天一定要较量一下
We must have a few fast falls together some time.
老史 如果他有答案…
Hey, Strap! He's got the right answers.
…我们不必亲赴现场 手下能应付一切
You and me don't even have to be there. The boys can handle everything.
他们把壁炉封闭了
Hey, they closed up the fireplace!
- 我不喜欢这样 - 怎么回事？
- I don't like this! - What's going on here?
毒气！
The gas!
可惜 你选择不加入其他人
Such a pity you did not choose to remain with the others, Mr Solo. However…
邦德先生 我以为你在睡房休息
Mr Bond, I thought you were resting in your quarters.
睡得很舒适！不过天气太好了 还是出来走走
They are delightful. But it's much too nice to stay indoors.
我碰上葛小姐 她建议我们加入你
I ran into Miss Galore and she suggested that we join you.
这是索先生 这是邦德先生 我另一位贵宾
Mr Solo, Mr Bond. Another of my distinguished guests.
- 哈喽 - 索先生 这么快要走？
- Hello. - Leaving us so soon, Mr Solo?
- 很不幸 他另外有紧急的约会 - 我想动身了 金手指
- He has a pressing engagement. - Yeah. I'd like to get started, Goldfinger.
- 小子 - 该走的时候就走
- Boy! - When you gotta go, you gotta go.
我的飞机会准时送你到纽约…
My plane will get you to New York on time.
…和你超多的行李
with your excess luggage.
让我来
Allow me.
我的司机是个好司机 你马上就会到机场
My chauffeur's an excellent driver. You will be at the airport in a few minutes.
再会 索先生 也许下次吧
Goodbye, Mr Solo. Some other time, perhaps?
平安落地
Happy landings, old boy.
我在模型下发现他
I found him under the model.
满贯行动！我喜欢你的简报
Operation Grand Slam. I did enjoy your briefing.
我也是
So did I.
他出发了！
He's on the move.
慢点 别太近
Slow down, don't crowd him.
你瞎了吗？你错过转弯了
Are you blind or something? You missed the turn!
他们前面右转了
They've turned to the right just ahead here somewhere.
你这位老朋友去哪里？
Where's this old pal of yours headed?
十赌一 他去找女人或喝酒
Ten'll get you one, it's a drink or a dame.
收不到了
Dead.
- 也许是机件故障 - 除非他关掉
- Mechanical failure, maybe? - Unless he switched it off.
他为何这么做？
Why would he do that?
- 我们只能开去农场 - 好
- Drive to the farm, it's all we can do. - Right.
你在满贯行动分到的 足够让你成为富婆
Your share of Operation Grand Slam will make you a very rich woman, my dear.
否则我为何参与？
Why else would I be in it, Mr Goldfinger?
你会在英国养老吧？
You'll retire to England, I suppose?
不 我看中巴哈马 之中的一个小岛
No, I've spotted a little island in the Bahamas.
我会挂起“不准进入”的牌子…
I'll hang up a sign, "no trespassing",
…然后回归自然
and go back to nature.
- 基区 什么事？- 两个人乘一部车带着望远镜
- Yes, Kisch? - Two men in a car with binoculars.
赌徒寻找赛马消息
Touts looking for racing tips.
还有另一个可能
There's another possibility, however.
叫邦德先生加入我们
Kisch, ask Mr Bond to join us.
如果那些人是邦德的朋友
We were right to spare Mr Bond's life in Switzerland,
我们在瑞士放他一命就做对了
if those gentlemen are his friends.
我们说服他们 他不需要协助
Let's convince them he needs no assistance.
为了他们的福利 让他尽量快乐
For their benefit, Pussy, let's make him as happy as possible.
我建议你换件更适合的衣服
I suggest you change into something more suitable.
当然
Certainly.
先公后私
Business before pleasure.
他找你
He wants you.
邦德先生 请坐
Mr Bond. Sit down, please.
薄荷茶？
Mint julep?
- 传统口味 还不错 - 好 谢谢
- Traditional, but satisfying. - Yes, thanks.
酸麦的 但请不要太甜
Sour mash, but not too sweet, please.
金手指 你令我失望
You disappoint me, Goldfinger.
满贯计划不会成功
You know Operation Grand Slam simply won't work.
顺便说一下 这神经毒气会致命
And incidentally Delta 9 nerve gas is fatal.
你消息还是一样灵通
You are unusually well informed, Mr Bond.
你会让六万人死得不明不白
You'll kill 60, 000 people uselessly.
美国每两年车祸 死亡人数就这么多
Ha! American motorists kill that many every two years.
没错 而我自己也计算一下
Yes, well… I've worked out a few statistics of my own.
150亿元金块
$15 billion.
重达1万5百吨
in gold bullion weighs 10, 500 tons.
六十人要搬十二天…装载在2百辆卡车上
60 men would take 12 days to load it onto 200 trucks.
你顶多只有两小时…
At the most, you'll have two hours.
…在陆海空军到达之前 搬货
before the army, navy, air force, marines move in and make you put it back.
谁说要搬走？
Who mentioned anything about removing it?
饮料够吗？
Is the julep tart enough for you?
你计划闯入世界最大的银行…
You plan to break into the world's largest bank.
…却不偷东西？
but not to steal anything.
为什么？
Why?
邦德先生 继续
Go on, Mr Bond.
林先生 中共派驻工厂代表…
Mr Ling, the Red Chinese agent at the factory?
…他是核子分解专家
He's a specialist in nuclear fission…
原来如此 他的政府要给你个炸弹
But of course! His government's given you a bomb.
我情愿叫做原子装置
I prefer to call it an atomic device.
很小 很脏
It's small but particularly dirty.
- 钴和碘？- 没错
- Cobalt and iodine? - Precisely.
如果你引爆诺克斯堡…
If you explode it in Fort Knox, the…
…全美的黄金的存货…将会受幅射影响…
…entire gold supply of the United States will be radioactive for…
…57年
…57 years.
正确说来是58年
58, to be exact.
我抱歉 真是启发性的交易
I apologise, Goldfinger. It's an inspired deal.
他们得到他们要的 西方经济危机
They get what they want, economic chaos in the West.
你的黄金价值提升好几倍
And the value of your gold increases many times.
保守估计十倍
I conservatively estimate… ten times.
精明
Brilliant.
而你所谓的原子装置…
But the atomic device, as you call it,
…显然已经在这国家里
is already, obviously, in this country.
没错
Obviously.
但放进诺克斯堡
But bringing it to Fort Knox undetected.
而不被侦测到 很冒险
could be risky. Very risky.
正好相反 你们才冒险
On the contrary, Mr Bond. The risk is all on your side.
如果你们想去寻找
If the authorities should attempt to locate it,
谁知道会在哪里爆炸
who knows where it might be exploded?
也许停泊在新伦敦的潜艇
Perhaps the Polaris submarine pens at New London,
在肯尼迪角？
Cape Kennedy,
靠近白宫？
near the White House.
我们仔细计划过了 满贯行动会成功的
But we are speculating idly. Operation Grand Slam will be successful.
你会当场见到
You will be there to see for yourself.
大概会很不舒服
Too closely for comfort, I'm afraid.
失陪了
Forgive me, Mr Bond,
我必须由故索先生身上 拿回黄金
but I must arrange to separate my gold from the late Mr Solo.
如你所说 他有个很急的约会
As you said, he had a pressing engagement.
很美 葛小姐！不是吗？
Very chic, Miss Galore. Don't you agree?
普西 款待邦德先生
Please entertain Mr Bond for me, Pussy.
我马上回来
I'll join you both later.
帅哥 如何？
How about it, handsome?
你不觉得我们应该 趁次机会认识彼此？
Don't you think it's time we got to know each other socially?
新的葛小姐
The new Miss Galore.
你把金手筘藏在这身衣服哪里？
Where do you hide your gold knuckles in this outfit?
我下班后从不带武器
I never carry weapons after business hours.
是吗？原来你不当值了
Yeah? So you're off duty?
我毫无防备
I'm completely defenceless.
我也是
So am I.
这才是我的詹姆斯
That's my James!
金手指的地方很美
Beautiful place Goldfinger has here.
是 很高兴你喜欢
Yes, I'm glad you're enjoying it.
太可惜了 明早一切就毁了
Too bad it all has to end tomorrow morning.
你知道 他有点疯了
He's quite mad, you know.
这里面有什么？
Well, now. What do we have here?
007似乎把情形处理得很好
007 seems to have the situation well in hand.
我累了 回酒店去吧
Come on, I'm bushed. Let's get back to the motel.
- 你是很不平凡的女孩 - 我生性好动
- You're quite a girl, Pussy. - I'm strictly the outdoor type.
我想你没有参与整件事
I'd like to think you're not in all of this… caper.
不谈了 我没有兴趣 走吧
Skip it. I'm not interested. Let's go.
要怎样才能让你以 我的方式看事情？
What would it take for you to see things my way?
你没有那能力
A lot more than you've got.
- 你怎么知道？- 我不想知道
- How do you know? - I don't want to know.
遵照将死的人的要求 是否为惯例？
Isn't it customary to grant a condemned man his last request?
你自找的
You've asked for this.
起来
Get up!
当然
Certainly.
现在让我们一起来
Now let's both play.
普西呼叫香槟领队
Pussy Galore to Champagne leader.
指挥摇摆宝贝 祝好运
Commence Rockabye Baby. Good luck!
速度：220
Speed: 220.
风向：西风
Wind check: Westerly.
香槟领队呼叫香槟队员 准备俯冲！
Champagne leader to Champagne section. Commence dive… now.
准备摇摆宝贝
Ready for Rockabye Baby.
喷洒开始倒数
Commence spray on countdown.
五
Five,
四 三 二
four, three, two,
零
zero.
香槟领队呼叫满贯行动领队
Champagne leader to Grand Slam task force leader.
宝贝已睡着
The baby is asleep.
重复 宝贝已睡着 我们回去了
I repeat, the baby is asleep. We're going home now.
完毕
Out.
早 邦德先生
Good morning, Mr Bond.
这次你终于 在我想你在的地方了
For once, you are exactly where I want you.
- 炸弹在此 - 出发吧 准将
- The bomb's here. - Let's get moving, Brigadier.
- 好 出发 - 以作战战形出发
- Right, Jack, move in. - Move in, commando tactics.
直到炸弹解除前 只做防卫性开火
Minimum offensive fire until I signal bomb has been neutralised.
炸弹拆除小组待命
Bomb disposal unit to accompany DOG.
再见 邦德先生
Goodbye, Mr Bond.
现在只是时间问题而已
Mr Ling, it is merely timing…
他也是一员 女孩也是！
He's one of them, so is the girl.
我去抓他 你们把门打开
I'll get her, you get the door open.
我们被困住了
We're trapped!
炸弹 我要把信管拿掉
The bomb… I'll take the fuse out.
别当傻子！
Don't be a fool!
你当英雄 我不要
You can be a hero, I'm not!
不 不
No, no!
走 快点！
Keep going! Hurry up!
什么事耽搁你？
What kept you?
还好吧？那位管家朋友呢？
You OK, James? Where's your butler friend?
他弄坏了保险丝
He blew a fuse.
再多三秒 金手指就成功了
Three more ticks and Mr Goldfinger would've hit the jackpot.
- 抓到他了吗？- 还没 他跑不远
- Did you get him? - Not yet, but he won't get far.
- 普西呢？- 是她帮我们换过毒气瓶
- And Pussy? - She helped to switch the canisters.
什么使她通知华府的？
By the way, what made her call Washington?
我一定启发了她母性的本能
I must have appealed to her maternal instincts.
詹姆斯 上机 别让总统等太久
Come on, James. Get aboard. You can't keep the President waiting.
专机 白宫吃午餐 为什么？
Special plane, lunch at the White House. How come?
总统要亲自谢你
The President wants to thank you personally.
- 这没有什么 - 我知道 但他不知道
- It was nothing, really. - I know that, but he doesn't.
我想我可以在机上喝杯酒
I suppose I'll be able to get a drink here.
我通知空中小姐 准备三人份的酒
I told the stewardess liquor for three.
- 另外两人是谁？- 没有别人
- Who are the other two? - There are no other two.
- 再见 费立斯 - 再见 祝好运
- Goodbye, Felix. - So long. Good luck.
- 谢谢 - 祝好运
- Thank you, Brigadier. - Good luck.
欢迎你登机
I'm glad to have you aboard, Mr Bond.
恭喜你升官了 金手指
Well, congratulations on your promotion, Goldfinger.
- 也要去白宫进午餐吗？- 两小时候 我就会在古巴
- Are you going to the White House, too? - In two hours I shall be in Cuba.
这是你最后一次破坏我计划
You have interfered with my plans for the last time, Mr Bond.
机内开枪很危险 我甚至也警告过普西
It's very dangerous to fire guns in planes. I even had to warn Pussy about it.
- 她在哪儿？- 我等会处置她
- By the way, where is she? - I will deal with her later.
她在她该在的地方 驾驶舱
She is where she ought to be… at the controls.
普西
Pussy!
- 怎么了？金手指呢？- 去弹金竖琴了
- What happened? Where's Goldfinger? - Playing his golden harp.
不是好现象
It's no good.
你不可以！
Oh, no, you don't!
此刻不适合被救援
This is no time to be rescued.